Every family tree hides a secret.
Hereditary is a horror, mystery, thriller film directed by Ari Aster.
Following the death of the Leigh family matriarch, Annie and her
children uncover disturbing secrets about their heritage.
Their daily lives are not only impacted, but they also become entangled in a chilling
fate from which they cannot escape, driving them to the brink of madness.
Annie Graham, played by Toni Collette.
Peter Graham, played by Alex Wolff.
Steve Graham, played by Gabriel Byrne.
Charlie Graham, played by Milly Shapiro.
Joan, played by Ann Dowd.
Bridget, played by Mallory Bechtel.
Hereditary is a 2018 American supernatural psychological
horror film written and directed by Ari Aster.
Starring Toni Collette, Alex Wolff, Milly Shapiro, Ann Dowd, and Gabriel Byrne, the film follows Annie Graham, a
grieving miniature artist who uncovers disturbing secrets about her recently deceased mother.
She, along with her husband Steve and their children, Peter and
Charlie, are subsequently tormented by sinister occurrences.
Aster's work on short horror films, most notably The Strange Thing About the Johnsons,
attracted the attention of A24, who greenlit Hereditary as his first feature film.
Aster conceived it as primarily a family drama
consisting of two distinct halves.
Principal photography commenced in Salt Lake City in February 2017, with most of the indoor scenes
shot on custom built sets on a soundstage to give the film a dollhouse aesthetic.
Hereditary premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on January 21, 2018, and
was theatrically released in the United States on June 8.
The film received critical acclaim, and was a commercial success,
grossing $90 million against its $10 million production budget.
It is regarded as one of the best horror films of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of daughter, funeral, parent child
relationship, loss of loved one, ritual.
The tone is intense and lighthearted and dark.